Okay, so in this video then, we're going
to just explain a few other common
procurement terms that you would need to
know about for the P&P exam.
Okay, so the first term I want to cover is
this one called the
Qualified Vendors List.
And really, as the name suggests,
Qualified Vendors List is just listing a
list of vendors that
you might consider that
are qualified to actually
perform the work.
So, as a simple example, it could be a
list of your preferred vendors.
They're already pre-qualified.
Or let's say you're reaching out to new
vendors.
So we are looking at the source selection
criteria.
They basically meet the source selection
And so these are a list of vendors that
are qualified now.
These are the list of
vendors that you could
reach out to and send an
RFP and so and so forth.
Another term, another important term,
I want to mention, this one here called
the letter of intent, LOI, letter of
intent.
Now, the key thing about letter of intent
is it's not a legally binding document.
There are many, many different ways of
using an LOI.
There's no right or wrong way of using a
letter of intent.
There's many, many different ways.
So, for example, write the beginning of a
contract, right, even before you send out
an RFP, even before the buyer sends an RFP
to the seller.
Sometimes, especially if it's a big, huge,
large project,
multi-billion-dollar project.
You send an RFP to the seller.
It may take them several weeks just to get
a team together to work on the RFP.
So, a lot of times, the seller
might want to see some
kind of letter, some kind
of letter of intent, an LOI.
Before they receive the RFP, they want to
see some kind of LOI, letter of intent,
so that now they can get a team together.
Like I said, it may take them a few weeks.
They can spend that time getting a team
together so that once they actually
receive the RFP, they
now have a team together
and they can start working on the RFP.
So that's one way of looking at a letter
of intent.
Another way of looking at a letter of
intent is right at the end of contract
negotiation when you could be summarizing
all of the terms and conditions of the
contract that everybody
is signing just so that both
parties know and understand
exactly what they're signing.
And there's many, many, many different
ways in between.
Like I said, there's no right or wrong way
of using a letter of intent.
The main thing about
letter of intent is it's
essentially saying, we are
thinking of hiring you, right?
So we meaning we as a buyer are thinking
of hiring this seller.
We're thinking of hiring this seller.
but it's not legally binding.
That's the biggest thing.
It is not legally binding.
Then you might come across this term here
called privity.
And privity refers to a contractual
relationship between two parties.
A contractual relationship between the
buyer and the seller.
So you being the buyer, you're the buyer,
you have a contract
with your primary vendor.
So that means you are in privity.
You have legal obligation over them.
They have legal obligation over you,
right?
So that means that you are in privity with
them and they are in privity with you.
Now, under the terms and conditions of the
contract, your primary vendor may be
allowed to outsource some of their work or
even all of their work, but they may be
allowed to outsource their work to their
subcontractor.
You have no authority over their
You do not have a contract with their
subcontractor.
So you cannot delegate any work to them.
You cannot even communicate with them,
right, with their subcontractor.
You are not in privity with their
subcontractor.
You are in privity with your primary
vendor that you have a contract with.
So all of your delegation and
communication has to be via your primary
vendor that you have a contract with,
not with a subcontractor.
So, like I said, you can't even
communicate with them.
You are not imprivile with their
subcontractor.
Another common term that you might come
across, this term here, called an escrow.
And if any of you have
ever purchased a property
in the US, right, you all
know what an escrow is.
right, you purchase, or rather,
as you're purchasing your property,
you put some money down,
earnest money, and in an escrow,
and nobody has access to
that, right, until the closing.
And that's exactly the same principle.
It doesn't have to be money, though.
It could be with property or even
intellectual property, right, it's placed,
or mutually placed into
the custody of a third party
until, you know, this particular
condition has been led.
Alright, so as a very simple example,
let's say you have hired a small
consulting firm to write a piece of code,
a small piece of proprietary code,
right, so to develop a module that is just
used for your team or your department.
No one else in the organization uses it,
right?
It's just specifically
for your, you know, for
either for your team
or for your department.
Any time your organization does assist,
any time your organization does a systems
upgrade, then this company that you've
hired, this consulting firm that you've
hired, they will do the necessary upgrade
to the code and to the module.
Now, what happens if this company goes out
of business?
There are a small consulting firm.
They could go out of business at any time.
So what you will do,
you as a buyer, right,
is, you will ask to put
this code in an escrow.
So some third party is going to be looking
after this piece of code.
So that in the event, if this person,
or rather in the event, if this consulting
firm goes out of business, that code is
going to be released to you.
Otherwise, you have no access to that
code.
And if you don't place it in an escrow,
if that company goes out of business,
you basically lost everything.
So that's why to protect you.
protect yourself, protect your code or
protect your module.
If that company goes out
of business, you want to still
have access so you could
put the coding into an escrow.
There's another very simple example of an
escrow there.
Another term you might come across is this
one called a force major.
A force major is a clause and a contract.
It's a contract clause.
It's basically saying that
neither party can be held liable
for non-performance of work
due to factors beyond our control.
Factors beyond our control
basically refers to, you
know, something
unpredictable and uncontrollable.
Something negative, something sudden.
So we have no control of it.
So literally things like tsunamis,
hurricanes, right?
Earthquakes, rioting, we have no control
over that.
So we cannot be held
liable for non-performance
of work due to those kinds of things.
of factors.
So that is a clause on a contract and it's
known as a fourth major.
Okay, otherwise referred to as an act of
God.
Sometimes it's referred to as an act of
All right, so these are a couple of,
or just a few additional common terms that
you need to be aware of, right,
if you ever see this on the P&P exam.